American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIi. 1897 APS.Archives.IIi APS.Archives.IIi
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIi
1897
APS.Archives.IIi
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Jan. 1, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Horn, Katherine S.
    Scope and Contents note
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Report on G.H. Horn's health.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 2, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p., end. International exchange.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 3, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Nominates Coleman Sellers for Vice President.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 3, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Nominates G.F. Edmunds to fill Hartshorne's term as Councillor.
  - Letter to Richard Rathbun, Jan. 4, 1897; 9x5-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., L. 2p. Copy Concerns international exchanges.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 4, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns report of Secretaries.
  - Letter to the Academie Royale de Belgique, Jan. 4, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L. with MS. addition 1p. In French Copy Tells of Phillips' death.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 4, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Vice President.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 4, [1897]; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns plate for printing membership certificates.
  - Letter to unidentified recipient, Jan. 5, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Copy Concerns rules for election to A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 5, 1897; 10x8-1/2; Missouri. Bureau of Geology and Mines
    Jefferson City, Typed L.S.: C[harles] R[ollin] Keyes 1p., end. Concerns package wrongly delivered.
  - Letter to Frank Hamilton Cushing, Jan. 6, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Copy Pleads for Ms. of his paper.
  - Letter to [Katherine S.] Horn, Jan. 6, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Inquiry about Dr. Horn's health. Asks for key to safe, as Librarian pro tem.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 6, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Kellar, John A.
    St. Charles, Mo., A.L.S. 2p. Offers to guide parties to sites for archaeological and zoological research.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 6, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Miller, G. A. (George Abram), 1863-1951
    Paris, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks if A.P.S. publishes papers on mathematics.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 7, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his paper, "Exploration of ancient Key-dwellers' remains on the Gulf Coast of Florida." For printed paper, see: APS proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 7, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Recommends various engraving companies.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Jan. 7, [1897]; 5-3/4x3-1/2; Horn, Katherine S.
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Report on Horn's health.
  - Letter to J[ames] C[heston] Morris, Jan. 9, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Maine Historical Society
    Portland, Me., A.L.S.: H[ubbard] W[inslow] Bryant 2p. Asks for seal for its certificate. Will exchange duplicate bookplates.
  - Letter to Samuel H[ubbard] Scudder, Jan. 10, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. with MS. corrections 1p. Copy Concerns printing of his paper. Refers to Horn's illness.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 10, 1897; 6-3/4x5-1/2; Ortmann, A. E. (Arnold Edward), 1863-1927
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper, "Natural Selection and Separation." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 175-192.
  - Note concerning Eadward Muybridge's gift of plates, Jan. 11, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.D. 1p.
  - Note to [Persifor] Frazer, Jan. 11, [1897]; 5-3/4x3-1/2; Horn, Katherine S.
    [Phila.], A.N. in 3d person 1p. Report on Horn's health.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 11, 1897; 10-1/2x8; New Hampshire State Library
    Concord, N.H., Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Arthur H. Chase, State Librarian 1p. and end. Asks for A.P.S. publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 12, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Dainton, John James
    Meriden, Conn., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Inquires about Proceedings.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 12, 1897; 8x5; Mallet, John William
    Charlottesville, Va., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns payment for Proceedings. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Jan. 12, 1897; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. APS business. Refers to Mallet.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 13, 1897; 12-1/2x8; Muybridge, Eadweard, 1830-1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Offers photographic plates.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 13, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Winship, George Parker, 1871-1952
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks bibliographical question about Rincon, Arte Mexicana, 1595. Refers to J.C. Pilling.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 14, [1897]; Emmens, Stephen N.
    P.D. Mss. filled in. 1p. Submits paper on gravitation, which, if correct will "introduce modifications into the laws and doctrines now accepted and taught in all branches of physical science."
  - Letter to George F[rederick] Barker, Jan. 14, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Copy Sends note to be answered.
  - Letter to J[ohn] W[illiam] Mallet, Jan. 14, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Copy Concerns payment for Proceedings. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Jan. 15, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Winship, George Parker, 1871-1952
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Pilling's work in Mexican linguistics, which Winship is completing.
  - Minutes of meeting, January 15, 1897; 9x6; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    A.D.S.: J[ames] Cheston Morris 1p.
    Not Found: 4/2011
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 16, 1897; 11-1/4x8-3/4; Levytype Co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Estimate for plates for Mercer's paper on the sloth. For Printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 36-70.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 17, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his paper on archaeological excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 17, 1897; 6-1/2x5-1/4; Leonard, Charles Lester, 1861-1913
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting Concerns printing of his paper. Refers to Dr. Pepper and Dr. Stengle.
  - Telegram to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 18, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, D. 1p. Gives estimate for illustrations for his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Telegram to F[rank] H[amilton] Cushing, Jan. 19, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., D. 1p. Copy. Concerns illustrations for Cushing's paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 19, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, [Pa.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns meeting with Sachse.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Jan. 20, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Will begin work of Committee on Revision of the Laws.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 20, 1897; 10-3/4x7-3/4; Weeks, William R.
    Newark, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks about material pertaining to the founding of Princeton.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 21, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Orders copies of the "Tribute Roll of Montezuma" (in APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 53-61), for J.F. Loubat.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 21, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Kegan Paul, Trench, Trübner & Co., Ltd.
    London, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Sends payment.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 21, 1897; 8x5; Ritter, John F
    Muncy, Pa., A.L.S. 3p., end. Offers old Bible and coins for sale.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 21 to July 19, 1897; Lemcke & Buechner
    New York, L. 3 items, 2 of them on postal cards Various sizes. Orders for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 22, 1897; 11x8-1/4; Slocum, Alfred M., co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Do not want to print Proceedings.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 22, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Change of address for Matthaüs Much.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 22, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Cyrus Adler 2p. Lists some sources for information on learned societies.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 25, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Promises MS. of his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Jan. 25, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. end. Copy Asks him to contribute to symposium on petroleum.
  - Translation of an impression from the Chinese block in the possession of the American Philosophical Society, Jan. 25, 1897; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p. For block, see accession no.: 58-43. Location: Philosophical Hall. Drafts of translation...11 leaves. Various sizes.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 25, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks to examine Franklin letters in A.P.S. collection.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 26, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Horn, Philip H.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1P. Concerns G.H. Horn's health. Gives his opinion on papers by Scudder and Dr. Fischer.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 27, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Foote, Albert E., Co.
    Phila., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns sale of Proceedings.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, January 27, 1897; 81/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Forwards request of T. Williams to examine Franklin letters. For enclosure, see: Williams to Fraley, January 25, 1897.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 27, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; De Gregorio, Antonio, marchese, 1855-1930
    Palermo, []. A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. In French Wants to submit paper (on fossils?) With transcript in Frazer's handwriting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 28, 1897; 8x5; Bolton, Henry Carrington, 1843-1903
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Inquires about early Phila. chemical society. Refers to Robert Hare and his oxyhydrogen blowpipe.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 28, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown,[pa.,] L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to T [sic] M[inis] Hays, Jan. 28, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Science
    Garrison-on-Hudson, N.Y., Typed L.S.: J[ames] Mck[een] Cattell 1p. Cannot exchange.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 28, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Smith, Goldwin, 1823-1910
    Toronto, L.S. 2p., end., and end. Letter of resignation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Bailey, L. H. (Liberty Hyde), 1858-1954
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for certificate of membership.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Baird, Henry Martyn, 1832-1906
    Yonkers, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for certificate of membership.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1897; 6x4; Bispham, George Tucker, 1838-1906
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for certificate of membership.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1897; 8x5; Carter, James C. (James Coolidge), 1827-1905
    [New York], A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Foggo, Edward Abraham, 1834?-1898
    Phila. A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Goodspeed, Arthur W. (Arthur Willis), b. 1860
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Harrison, Charles Custis, 1844-1929
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1897; 8x5; Pickering, Edward C. (Edward Charles), 1846-1919
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Note to the [American philosophical society;], Jan. 29, 1897; 8x5; Tower, Charlemagne, 1848-1923
    Phila.], A.N. in 3rd person 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 30, 1897; 11x8-1/2; A. S. Barnes & Co.
    New York, L. 1p. Requests use of Wilder's illustrations for paper on brain of a cat. Letter pasted to one from Price to Hays, Feb. 8, 1897.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 30, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Ewell, Marshall Davis, 1844-1928
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 30, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Kennelly, Arthur E. (Arthur Edwin), 1861-1939
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 30, 1897; 9x8; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illiam] A. Pickell, Sec'y. 1p. Concerns printing of Memorial Volume I.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 30, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Minot, Charles Sedgwick, 1852-1914
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 30, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Putnam, F. W. (Frederick Ward), 1839-1915
    Cambridge, Mass., L.S.: Jane Smith, Librarian 1p., end. Thanks for Putnam's membership certificate.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 30, 1897; 8x5, 11-3/4x9-1/4; Wright, Joseph, 1855-1930
    L. 2p., end. Enc. of 4p. printed leaflet Sends prospectus for English Dialect Dictionary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 31, 1897; 8x5; Gibbs, J. Willard (Josiah Willard), 1839-1903
    New Haven, [Conn.] A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 1, 1897; 11-1/4x8-1/2; Dana, Edward Salisbury, 1849-1935
    New Haven, Conn., Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 1, 1897; 8x5; Hyatt, Alpheus, 1838-1902
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Feb. 1, 1897; 8x5; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    A.L.S. 1p. Will superintend Levy's work.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 1, 1897; 11-1/4x8-1/2; Michigan. Geological Survey
    Houghton, Mich., Typed L.S,.: Alfred C[hurch] Lane 1p., end. Asks for copies of Winchell's papers.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Feb. 1, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Michigan. Geological Survey
    Houghton, Mich., Typed L.S.: Alfred C[hurch] Lane 1p. Exchange of publications. Refers to A. Winchell.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Feb. 1, 1897; 10x8; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Sends two papers on petroleum. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 116-126.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 1, 1897; 11-3/4x8; Princeton University
    Princeton, Printed, L.filled in in MS., S.: Francis L[andey] Patton 1p. Acknowledges appointment of C. Biddle as APS representative to its sesquicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], Feb. 1, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Introduces a Mr. Duffy, who wants to see Franklin letters.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 2, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Elliott, A. Marshall
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 2, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Hyvernat, Henri, 1858-1941
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Orders copies of Hilprecht's papers on Babylonian inscriptions. For printed papers, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 5-54, 221-282.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Feb. 2, 1897; 10x8; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Asks to withdraw one of two papers on petroleum.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morison, Feb. 2, 1897; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns the marquis de Rochambeau.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 2, 1897; 8x5; Welch, William Henry, 1850-1934
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Feb. 3, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Concerns illustrations for his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 3, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 2p., end. Lists his appointments to standing committees.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 4, 1897; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Bement, Clarence S. (Clarence Sweet), 1843-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for certificate of membership.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 4, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Brooke, Arthur S.
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p., end. Requests that Scientific American be allowed use of plates from Hilprecht's paper.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Feb. 4, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Day, David T. (David Talbot), 1859-1925
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends MS. of his remarks made at symposium on petroleum. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 112-115.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Feb. 4, 1897; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Concerns committee on lecture programme. Refers to Fraley.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Feb. 4, 1897; 11-1/4x8-3/4; Levytype Co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Business matter.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 4, 1897; 8x5; McCook, Henry C. (Henry Christopher), 1837-1911
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Feb. 4, 1897; 10x8; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Asks to alter a paper on petroleum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 4, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Scientific American
    New York, Typed L. 1p., end. Concerns use of plates from Hilprecht's paper. Refers to A.S. Brooke.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Feb. 4, [1897]; 7x4-1/2; Furness, William Henry, 1866-1920
    Wallingford, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. concerns his paper on Borneo. Refers to H.M. Hiller. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 321-328.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Feb. 5, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Wishes to submit paper on petroleum, to be published with papers read at symposium on that subject. For printed papers on petroleum, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 92-140.
  - Letter to I. Minis Hays, Feb. 5, [1897]; Price, John sergeant, 1831-1897
    A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 5, [1897]; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns engravers.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 6, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Catholic University of America
    Washington, A.L.S.: Achille Deleine (?) 1p., end. Enc. wanting Sends payment for volume of Transactions.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Feb. 6, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Fraley, Joseph Cresson, ca. 1848-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of Sesquicentennial report.
  - Letter to Lorin Blodget, Feb. 6, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Copy Concerns publication of papers from symposium on petroleum. For printed papers on petroleum, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 92-140.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Feb. 6, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Calls Library Committee meeting.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 6, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illiam] A. Pickell, Sec'y. 1p. Concerns Printing of Proceedings, no. 152.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 6, 1897; 8x5; Phelps, Edward John, 1822-1900
  - Note to the [American philosophical society], Feb. 6, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Taylor, Isaac, 1829-1901
    Malton, [Eng.], A.N. in 3d person 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Feb. 6, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Wilson, Joseph M. (Joseph Miller), 1838-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to Committee on Hall.
  - Letter to [John James] Stevenson, Feb. 6, [1897]; 9x5-3/4, 13x8; Pennsylvania Forestry Association
    [Phila.], A.L.S.: Mary S. Sandy 2p. and end. Enc. of 2p. typed text with MS. corrections Concerns enclosed proposed resolution on state forests. Refers to Rothrock. For printed resolution, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 141-142.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Feb. 7, 1897; 8x5; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 10p. Concerns his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Feb. 7, 1897; 8x5; Fennell, C. A. M. (Charles Augustus Maude), d. 1916
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 7, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Huggins, William, Sir, 1824-1910
    London, Typed L.S. with MS. addition 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 7, [1897]; 7x4-1/2; Glazebrook, Richard, 1854-1935
    Cambridge, [Eng.] A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 8, 1897; 6-1/4x4-1/2; Bertin, Georges Eugène, 1847?-1910
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Acknowledges receipt of his diploma.
  - Note to the American philosophical society, Feb. 8, 1897; 3-3/4x4-1/2; Bonaparte, Roland, prince, 1858-1924
    Paris, A.N. in 3d person 1p. In French. Thanks for his diploma.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Feb. 8, 1897; 8x5; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 5p. Concerns his paper on excavations in Florida. Refers to Dr. Pepper. For Printed Paper, see: APS Proceedings Vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to Frank Hamilton Cushing, Feb. 8, 1897; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    D.S. 1p. Concerning drawings, asking for manuscript. Freeman Guide 1208.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 8, 1897; 6-3/4x8-1/4; Furness, William Henry, 1866-1920
    Wallingford, Typed L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends MSS. of his own and H.M. Hiller's.
  - Letter to William Pepper, Feb. 8, 1897; 11x8; Kennelly, Arthur E. (Arthur Edwin), 1861-1939
    Phila., Typed L.S. 2p. Will write short paper on insulated conductors with E.J. Houston.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 8, 1897; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897